Guide to the Dr. Ellen Rosenberg's Religion in Society and Culture Student Paper Collection MS 041
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Dr. Ellen Rosenberg's Religion in Society and Culture Student Paper Collection
1975
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Rosenberg, Ellen MacGilvra, 1929-
MS 041
139
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
Dr. Ellen M. Rosenberg was a member of the anthropology department at Western Connecticut State University. This is a collection of research papers completed by students of her "Religion in Society and Culture" course in 1975. The papers profile congregations in the Danbury Area.
Provenance
Donated to the Archives in 2002.
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Historical/Biographical Note
Dr. Ellen Rosenberg is retired from the Anthropology department at Western Connecticut State University. Rosenberg received her A.B. from Sarah Lawrence College, an M.A. from Columbia University and a Ph.D. from the New School for Social Research. She is author of The Southern Baptists: A Subculture in Transition. In 1975, Western Connecticut State College offered ANT/SOC 232 - Religion and Culture, which analyzed religion as a universal aspect of human culture expressed as a belief and ritual concerned with supernatural beings, powers an forces. The course also involved discussions on the function of religion in society.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes research papers submitted for the ANT/SOC 232 - Religion and Culture course offered in the fall of 1975 at WestConn. Each paper profiles a different congregation in the Danbury area.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by author.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Missing Title
Inventory
Essays.; Danbury (Conn.); Danbury (Conn.) -- Church History.; Religions.; Ethnology -- Religious aspects.; Western Connecticut State University
- Inventory, 40803
  - Creator: Bag, N; Title: Southern Baptists, 1975; 40825 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Creator: Capra, Douglas R. Title: The Danbury Advent Christian Church, 1975; 40824 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Creator: Carmody, Patricia Title: St. Peter's Parish, 1975; 40823 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Creator: DeGrego, Dominic Title: St. Ann's Melkite Roman Catholic Church, 1975; 40822 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Creator: Eriksson, Sandra Title: King Street United Church of Christ, 1975; 40821 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Creator: Farah, Montez Title: Saint George Antiochian Orthodox Church of Danbury, Connecticut, 1975; 40820 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Creator: Filogomo, Vincent Title: First Church of Christ Scientist, 1975; 40819 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Creator: Garavel, Paul J. Title: Central Christian Church, 1975; 40818 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Creator: Hilelson, Phyllis Title: St. Nicholas Byzantine Catholic Church, 1975; 40817 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Creator: Lockwood, Lyn Title: The Immanuel Lutheran Church, 1975; 40816 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Creator: Louie, Carol and Josie Tompkins Title: The Salvation Army, 1975; 40815 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Creator: Mazzochi, Bruce Title: Sacred Heart of Jesus Parish, 1975; 40814 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Creator: Mitchell, James Title: St. Gregory the Great, Roman Catholic Church, 1975; 40813 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Creator: Palulis, RoseMarie Title: New Hope Baptist Church, Inc., 1895-1974, 1975; 40812 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Creator: Pinkham, Thomas Title: St. James Episcopal Church, 1975; 40811 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Creator: Rade, Mary Title: Assemblies of God, 42 Deer Hill Avenue, Danbury, 1975; 40810 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Creator: Ramos, Delfin R. Title: Holy Trinity Russian Orthodox Church, 1975; 40809 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Creator: Robinson, Carol and Ana Stein Title: Mt. Pleasant A.M.E. Zion Church, 1975; 40808 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Creator: Russo, Steve Title: St. Anthony's Maronite Catholic Church, 1975; 40807 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Creator: Santoro, William Title: Baptist Church of Danbury, 1975; 40806 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Creator: Taylor, Jan Title: Unitarian-Universalist Society of Northern Fairfield County, 1975; 40805 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Creator: Zeno, Kathleen Title: Jehovah's Witnesses, 1975; 40804 (Box 1, Folder 22)